[theme music playing]
[emcee] The beloved father
of our town has arrived! Governor Julio!
A very happy and prosperous
festival to all of us!
[crowd cheering]
[Dante] Yes, this is going to be
our new home!
The front yard is huge!
But why don't we have neighbors?
[Camia] No one will think
of doing us harm here.
[Julio] You're the one at fault
for all of this.
If a married couple is having problems,
it's always the wife's fault.
You… You and your weaknesses as a woman…
[Camia] The Ardientes must be
very important people.
[teacher] The Ardientes provide
for this town's needs.
We're all so grateful to their family.
We pay for everything the politicians
do for us with our taxes.
We don't owe them anything.
It's not their money.
[Julio] Each given year,
you fail one subject in school!
[Diego] Grandpa!
I have to be brave.
Hey, don't jump! Oh no!
Grab my hand! Hurry!
[Lily] You're hurt.
Do you want to come over?
No, thanks. My family
might be looking for me.
[Lily] Take care, Diego.
[Atty. Sta. Maria]
Legal battles are rare here.
For the past 15 years,
there's practically been no crime!
[Arthur] That's not true!
This place is pure evil!
There'll come a day
this town will cease to exist.
[Camia] You come all the way
here to study?
[Diego] Yes. It's quiet here.
-We can help you if you want.
-[Lily] My mom's a teacher.
You'll get better grades
if you let her help you.
-[Diego panting]
-[Lily] I'm tired!
[Lily] It's really beautiful here.
[shouting] I want to eat ice cream!
[exhales] Really?
-Yeah.
-Okay, I'll treat you to ice cream.
But you have to do
our exercises ten times first!
[Lily laughing]
So, do you still want ice cream?
[shouting] I don't want ice cream anymore!
[Lily laughing]
You changed your mind, huh?
Why do you always have that with you?
The Count of Monte Cristo.
I love it when my father reads this to me.
I like reading about people's lives
changing for the better.
No matter how poor you might be,
you could be rich one day. [chuckles]
Well…
being poor's fine
as long as I have a happy family.
Just like yours! That'd be great.
You can, though.
Just keep coming back to see us.
-Can I?
-Yes! Of course! Any time!
[shouting] Thank you, Lily!
Am I there?
-No.
-Am I deaf?
-No!
-Then you didn't have to shout!
[shouts] You're welcome, Diego!
-Like that?
-[both laughing]
-Let's go!
-Let's go there!
[Diego] What? I don't get it.
[Lily] Diego needs help, Mom.
I was trying to teach him,
but he still can't solve this.
[Camia] It's easy. Here…
[pensive music playing]
-[tense music playing]
-[inaudible]
-[Dante] Snack time!
-[Lily] Dad!
-Want some sandwiches?
-[Camia] Wow! Did you make these?
-[Dante] Of course!
-[Loring] Hey, Diego.
The driver's here to pick us up.
[Diego] Okay. Thank you.
-Bye!
-[Lily] Take care!
[Diego] Thank you!
-Come back, okay?
-[Diego] I'll be back!
[teacher 1] Let's all rise
and welcome the Ardiente Family!
A round of applause for them!
-[band playing lively tune]
-[people cheering and clapping]
Hi, Diego!
Hi, Lily.
Hi. I'm Raul Torillo.
I'm the husband of our lovely mayor.
Good afternoon, sir.
I'm Camia Cruz. I tutor Diego.
Thank you.
[tense music playing]
See you.
[crowd cheering]
[Julio] Education is a valuable thing.
Especially to the youth.
And last year, I noticed the lack of…
-Ms. Maan, I need to go to the restroom.
-…facilities…
-Sure.
-…in this school.
Just imagine
40 to 50 students
gathering in one classroom.
They must have felt
like sardines tightly packed
in one small can.
Where's the restroom?
-That way, sir.
-So, here, today…
I'll go to the restroom. Excuse me.
…I'm pleased to present
the newest building in this school!
[crowd clapping and cheering]
[foreboding music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[whistles]
Sir.
Sorry, I thought this was the men's room.
-The men's room's over there.
-Oh, is that so?
So, you're the one
tutoring my son for free.
You're so kind. Thank you.
-It's nothing. Excuse me.
-Wait.
Why are you in a hurry?
I still want to talk to you.
Sir, we can talk outside.
What's wrong with talking here?
Now I know why my son
is so inspired to study.
You're more beautiful up close.
Sir, please take your hands off me.
I'm just saying you're beautiful.
I said take your hands off me!
Don't touch me!
Sir! Let me go! Let me go!
-[pot breaking]
-[heavy breathing]
[Julio] Good day to everyone!
I hope you can make good use
of the new building.
[crowd clapping]
-Be careful, kids!
-Ms. Maan, where's Lily?
She's over there.
What happened to you?
Why are you shaking? Are you all right?
[music stops]
[Dante] What happened to you?
Lily said she saw you
trembling at school today.
What? It's nothing, hon.
I was just stressed.
There were a lot of people. How was work?
It was all right.
You know, I was thinking.
All the records I found
at the office say that this town
has an almost zero crime rate.
But there were a lot of accidents.
For example, car accidents
where people die.
Hon, where is this leading to?
All the crimes, ambush, murder,
all happened a few kilometers away
from the town boundaries.
All the people
who got involved with the Ardientes
were all found dead outside town.
-It might be a coincidence.
-And another thing.
There are graft charges
against Emilia and the Governor.
As for Raul Torillo,
he's got rape charges against him.
Stop this.
But hon, if it's true,
the victims need justice!
[tense music playing]
What are you doing? [moans]
You're so beautiful, Camia.
What did you say? Who's Camia?
What? I didn't say that.
-I heard you say "Camia".
-Shh. I didn't say anything.
-You said Camia. Who is she?
-Who's "Camia"?
I said, "Come here, Emilia."
You're such a liar.
You know what? You have a lot of issues.
I'm leaving.
ARDIENTE TOWN
What's that?
[Dante] My project.
-Jessica Vergara?
-You know her?
Oh, um…
Her name sounds familiar.
Uh… [sighs]
What is it? Murder or rape?
Both. More than five years ago.
She went missing
until her body was found floating
in a river a week later.
Before that, she allegedly
had an affair with Raul Torillo.
There are plenty of other victims
that are connected to the Ardiente family.
You'll get in trouble for that.
[Camia] Let go of me! Stop!
[pot breaking]
[exhales]
Did your wife tell you
about what happened yesterday at school?
What?
Dante! You're home early.
Are you tired?
Is it true you almost got raped yesterday?
[sighs]
Dante, it's over. Besides, nothing--
-Why didn't you tell me?
-I didn't want any trouble.
You're just going to keep quiet
after what he did?
-Nothing happened.
-He'll try again!
That was fun.
-I'll press charges!
-[Camia] Dante, let it go!
-Dad.
-Lily.
I'm with Diego.
Good afternoon.
[eerie music playing]
[gasps]
Don't worry. The wait is almost over.
Soon, I'll be able to avenge you.
[Dante] Jessica Vergara?
She went missing,
and her body was found floating
in a river a week later.
Before that, she allegedly
had an affair with Raul Torillo.
[Emilia] Congressman,
I heard that our rival party
has been raising funds for the election.
And there are two other candidates
who are running for governor,
Gopez and Marciano.
Don't mind them, Mayor.
They're just distractions in the election.
For sure, our people
still fully support the Ardientes.
[Emilia laughs]
[Julio] I agree.
I still believe that
our people are solid Ardiente supporters.
-Unwavering in their support. Solid.
-Solid.
So, when Emilia runs for governor,
Raul will be our next mayor.
Well, here's to victory!
-Cheers!
[chuckles]
[clears throat]
-So, congressman.
-Hmm.
Maybe you'd like to
introduce us to your companion.
Oh.
Everyone. This is Cinderella.
Cindy for short.
-Cinderella! [laughs]
-Yes.
What an interesting name!
Is it because your appearance
changes at midnight?
[laughs]
Yes, Auntie. I become more beautiful.
[moans]
[Emilia] So, Congressman,
where did you meet your date?
[chuckles] Mayor,
Congressman Enriquez introduced her to me.
I see! No wonder
she looks so familiar to me.
[gentle piano music]
[tense music]
[sighs]
-Hi!
-[both laughing]
[Cindy] Slow down. I might slip.
-Take your shoes off. Come on.
-It's slippery.
[Cindy chuckles] Hold on!
Congressman, would you
please excuse me for a while?
-Oh, sure!
-Thank you.
[Cindy giggling]
[Cindy] Hold on!
[tense music playing]
[Cindy moans]
[objects clatter]
What was that?
[Cindy] Something's burning. Let's go.
-Stop!
-Hey, wait!
-My hair is on fire!
-Wait. Hold on.
[Cindy] I said stop. I'm leaving!
-[Cindy] Where's it?
-[Raul] Fine, fine.
-Hey, where's my other shoe?
-I don't know!
[Emilia] Thank you so much
for coming. I hope you enjoyed dinner!
-Mayor, I have to go.
-Okay, Congressman.
[Emilia] Thank you. Thank you for coming.
Oh, by the way, Congressman,
your date seems to have
lost her other shoe.
Dante?
Please, let's not bring this to court.
They're powerful people.
ARDIENTE TOWN
Hello? I don't like it here.
I'm going back to Manila.
The Congressman's a cheapskate.
If you sue him,
we'll be the talk of the town.
It will affect Lily.
But if we both explain to her,
she'll understand.
Our daughter is smart.
She'll realize that
it's the right thing to do.
Yes, she's smart, just like you.
You're a great lawyer, but because of it,
a lot of people want to bring you down.
Hold on. I'll call you later, all right?
What's going on?
Why are they making me stop?
I'm scared I might see you dead
on the road one day.
Even when we're together, Dante…
[sighs] I'm still scared.
Because we could all get killed.
What is it?
[gunshot rings out]
[Camia] Dante, please.
Please don't stir up trouble.
And now, it's my fault.
That's what's wrong with the mentality
of people nowadays!
When violated, they just keep quiet
and allow themselves to become
victims over and over again!
Our passivity gives more power
to the wrong people!
We let them take advantage of us!
[Dante sighs]
Believe me. He'll keep trying
until he gets what he wants.
Camia, I'll fight for you.
Dante. I will also fight
for a happy and peaceful life.
Are you arguing?
[sighs]
No, Lily.
[phone ringing]
-Hello?
-[gunman] Good morning, ma'am.
The job's done.
[reporter on TV] Just this morning,
a woman's corpse was found
a few kilometers
outside the border of Poblacion Ardiente.
The woman was identified
as Cinderella Madlang-awa
from Malate, Manila.
Good job!
[tense music playing]
Poor Cinderella.
Oh. Breakfast?
It's the most important
meal of the day. Come.
[suspenseful music playing]
-Hi, Mom!
-Hi!
-Good morning.
Mom, I found your shoe in the pool.
[scoffs] Son, you know
I don't wear cheap shoes.
Maid, can you throw this out?
Go wash your hands.
Good morning, Dad and Mom.
Diego, where's your nanny?
She's inside.
Didn't she tell you that
from this day on, you're not
supposed to join us for meals?
Seriously, Emilia? He's a kid!
Diego.
Your food will be brought to your room
so we can control what you eat.
Why so sad?
You know I'm doing this for you, right?
Then, go back to your room now.
[sad music playing]
Come. Let's eat, son.
[Diego] What? Your family's leaving?
Yes.
I think so.
That's what I heard from Mom.
She said it'd be better if…
She said it'd be better if we left.
[cries]
Maybe it's not final yet.
I hope so.
I already like it here.
I don't want to leave.
I don't want to move houses again.
I thought we were finally
settling down here.
And if I leave,
who's going to be your friend?
[sniffles]
Who's going to exercise with you?
Who's going to help you
with your homework?
No one, that's for sure.
If you leave, no one
will make me happy anymore.
If you leave, I'll be alone.
I'll be lonely again.
I'll miss you.
Me too.
[Diego sobbing]
[knocking]
[foreboding music playing]
-What are you doing here?
-Where's Diego?
He's not here.
Good.
Wait, why are you coming in?
[heavy breathing]
I just want to give you these flowers.
I'm sorry. And thank you
for not filing a case against me.
I didn't do it because
our children are friends.
-How about us? Can we be friends?
-[panicked breathing]
Get away from me!
-Get out!
-[Raul] Hold on.
-You pervert!
-Wait!
Let's not fool ourselves anymore.
We both know that
we'll end up being friends.
I said get out!
Camia, I just want to be friends with you.
-Can you please just leave?
-Why should I?
-Is it so wrong to be friends with you?
-Raul, stay away.
Stay away! Get your hands off me!
[Camia shrieks]
Go away!
-Look at you?
-[grunts]
-[Raul grunting]
-[Camia panting]
[tense music]
[Lily] Mom!
-Mom!
-Dad!
-You bastard!
-Dad, stop it!
-Stop it!
-Dad, please stop!
-Dad!
-Dad, no!
-[Camia] Stop!
-[Lily] Dad!
-Dad!
-[both men grunting]
-[Lily] Stop it! That's enough!
-Dad!
-Dante, that's enough!
-Can you all leave us alone?
-[Camia] Leave us alone!
-Please stop! Stop it!
-[Dante and Raul panting]
-[Lily] Stop it!
I'll file a case against you. You'll see!
Come on. Let's go!
Diego!
[tense music playing]
Doc, I heard about what happened.
Nothing to worry about. I'll be on my way.
Okay. Thank you, Doc.
Thanks.
Can I see it?
The doctor said the cut isn't deep.
-It's nothing.
-Show me.
-I said it's nothing.
-Is that so?
[Raul screams]
[sighs] Diego, please go to your room now.
Honestly, I really wish
you'd use your head sometimes.
You do know Dante Cruz is a lawyer, right?
-So what?
-"So what"?
He can mean trouble for us.
He can talk about what happened
and my political rivals can use that.
It'll be a huge problem for my candidacy.
Are you an idiot?
If I'm an idiot, then you talk too much.
He won't be a problem. Have him killed!
-[scoffs]
-[pensive music]
[Dante] I told you he'd come back for you.
Are you okay?
I'm okay, hon.
Dad, I can't believe
Diego's father is a bad person.
It's a good thing we saw him,
or he could've done
something worse to Mom.
Lily, you remember
what I told you about
not trusting too easily, right?
You have to be careful.
You're a girl, and you're growing up fast.
If anyone touches you,
and you're not comfortable with it,
that's instinct telling you to get away.
I want you to learn
how to protect yourself
because your Mom and I
won't always be by your side.
Hon. I think Lily's too young for that.
Hon.
I want Lily to be prepared
for anything that might happen.
Promise me, Lily,
that you won't let yourself be abused
or harassed by anyone.
I promise, Dad.
You called for me, Papa?
It's the talk of the town.
Your devoted husband
couldn't keep his pants on again.
That man brings you nothing but shame.
Fix this, Emilia.
Our political enemies
might catch wind of this.
Yes, Papa.
That Dante Cruz,
he has already aggravated
a friend of mine from Manila.
He's not easy to silence.
-I'll take care of him, Papa.
-You do that.
For once, show me you've picked up
a thing or two from me.
[tense music playing]
DON JULIO ARDIENTE
PILLAR OF ARDIENTE TOWN
Attorney Cruz, the Mayor's
inviting you to her office.
Hold on.
[phone ringing]
Hello, Dante?
Hon, I was on my way home,
but the mayor wants to see me.
-What?
-[Dante] I won't take long, hon.
Don't worry about me. Goodbye.
Hello? Dante?
[man] Let's go, sir.
Hello?
Mayor, Attorney Cruz is here.
Attorney Dela Cruz! [chuckles]
-It's Cruz, not Dela Cruz.
-I'm so sorry.
I'm so bad with names.
I'm sure you understand.
I have so many
responsibilities as the mayor.
Have a seat.
-What is this about, Mayor?
-Attorney.
We both know why I called you here.
I'm sure you've heard
about the misunderstanding
between your wife and my husband.
What happened between
our spouses was no misunderstanding.
[scoffs] Whatever you call it, Attorney.
But we both
want to avoid trouble, don't we?
Maybe we can talk about this like adults.
We have nothing to talk about.
We're filing a lawsuit.
[scoffs] Dante! Dante.
I can call you Dante, right?
Besides, this is a personal conversation.
Honestly, I'm not doing this
for me or my family.
I'm doing this for you.
I don't want you to waste
your time, resources, or effort.
I'm sorry to say this, Attorney.
But you won't win.
Truth and justice are on my side.
Your position doesn't scare me,
even if you think you own this town.
[chuckles] How charming.
He thinks he's fighting back.
Calm down, Attorney.
You're too hot-headed.
All I'm saying is, don't waste your time.
Think about your family,
your beautiful wife,
and your young daughter.
They're precious.
Are you threatening me?
I'm not afraid of you! Nor your family.
Attorney.
I've never been fond of making threats.
Go ahead if you want to fight
for what's right.
All I'm saying is,
I won't back down, either.
[ominous music playing]
[tense music]
Arthur. What are you doing here?
The Mayor asked me to come.
I don't know why.
But I'm a little worried.
What about you? Why did she call you in?
[Dante sighs]
Are you okay?
Here.
Have some coffee.
[ominous music playing]
[Arthur] Why are you here?
[breathing heavily]
[exhales heavily]
[phone ringing]
-Hello, hon?
-I'm on my way home, hon.
Why is your voice shaking?
[breathing heavily]
-Hello, hon?
-[breathing heavily]
-Dante?
[grunts]
-Hello?
-[Dante grunting]
Dante?
[tires screech]
[vehicle crashes]
IN LOVING MEMORY OF
CAMIA, LILY
Dad.
[Lily] After the accident,
they conducted
an investigation and an autopsy.
Dante.
The results showed Dad
got into an accident…
Dante.
…because he suffered a heart attack.
Dad.
[indistinct chatter]
-Hi, Mayor.
-Hello, Mayor.
-Hi, friend.
-Good evening.
-Hello, Mayor
-Good evening. Hi. Sit down.
[man] Good evening, Mayor.
I'm sorry, Lily. My condolences.
-[sentimental music playing]
-Thank you.
My condolences, Mrs. Cruz.
I'm sorry for your loss.
It must've been so painful for you, huh?
How dare you?
You killed my husband!
You murderers! You killed my husband!
What are you talking about?
-[Camia] You monsters!
-[Emilia shrieks, gasps]
Leave! Get out of here!
Mom, calm down.
[gasps]
[Camia shouts] Get out!
-Mom, please don't.
-[Raul] Let's go.
It's okay. It's okay.
[people murmuring]
-[man 1] Are you okay, Mayor?
-It's okay. It's okay.
[Raul] It's okay, it's okay. Let's go.
[woman 1] Are you okay, Mayor?
[woman 2] Mayor, are you okay?
-I'm okay.
-[woman 3] Mayor…
[sentimental music playing]
[Lily sobbing]
Diego. Hurry up, okay?
Your parents can't find out
we came back here.
I just asked the driver a favor.
[Lily sobbing]
Lily.
[sentimental music playing]
[stammering]
He's gone…
My father is gone now.
Why did Mom say…
they killed Dad?
[crying] I'm so sorry, Lily.
I don't understand.
Sorry, Lily.
I don't know. I'm really sorry.
[phone ringing]
[Diego crying] I don't know!
[Lily wailing] He's dead!
It doesn't make sense!
I'm sorry, Lily!
Diego. Your dad's calling, Diego.
Lily!
-[Loring] We have to go now.
-Lily!
My father!
-[Loring] Let's go, Diego.
-Lily! I'm sorry!
[Diego crying] I'm sorry!
-Diego! Sorry, Lily.
-Lily! I'm sorry!
-I'm sorry!
-Let's go.
Bring back my father!
[Lily crying]
-[Lily crying]
-[Camia sobbing]
Dad.
Mom.
[melancholic music playing]
[Camia crying]
[Camia sobbing]
Mom.
Mom, you haven't gone to work in weeks.
I haven't been going to school.
What's going to happen to us now?
I don't know.
What are you saying?
-I don't know anymore!
-Mom.
I don't know! I don't know!
I don't know!
[Camia wailing]
Please don't cry. Mom.
Please don't cry.
[Camia wailing]
I'm sorry, Lily. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Here's what we'll do.
Listen to me, Lily. Pack your things.
We're leaving as soon as possible.
-Go on.
-Where will we go?
I don't know. Just pack up.
Hurry up! Go pack your things! Do it now!
Lily, hurry up!
Hurry up!
[shouts] Hurry!
[Camia sobbing]
Mom.
Lily, we'll go away.
That's what we should do now.
Go out and look for anything we can bring.
Go on.
[Camia sobbing]
[melancholic music playing]
[Lily crying]
Dad.
Dad, it's Mom.
[Lily] She needs you, Dad. We need you.
Please help us, Dad.
I miss you so much, Dad!
Dad!
Can you hear me from there?
[Camia sobbing]
I miss you so much, Dad!
Dad!
Dante.
[melancholic music playing]
DEAR LILY
[sobbing]
[rustling]
Dante?
[foreboding music playing]
Who's there?
Anybody there?
[foreboding music playing]
Who are you?
-Don't be scared.
-Why?
[gasps]
We're going to have fun.
Don't come any closer, I'm begging you.
[sobbing]
We'll play a game.
Please don't.
Don't.
Stay away from me! No!
[bleak music playing]
[foreboding music playing]
[suspenseful sting]
Mom?
[shushes]
Lily. Get out of here. Go.
-Run away!
-What happened to you?
[shushes] Get out of here!
Run, Lily! Run!
-Mom, what happened to you?
-Get out of here!
-Hey!
-[gasps]
Lily. Run!
-Run!
-What are you doing here?
[Camia] Hurry up!
[panting]
[gun cocking]
-Don't hurt my daughter!
-Let go of me!
[grunts]
No!
[Lily panting]
[suspenseful music playing]
Mom.
[whimpers]
Help. Help me!
Please help me! We need to save my mom!
-Take a seat first.
-Mom is at our house.
-Get her some water.
-Help her! Let's go back.
POLICE
-This way. She's inside.
-Wait for us here.
-Please hurry!
-Let's go.
[Lily] Mom? What happened to you?
-[shushes]
-[Tonio] Hey!
Lily. Run!
[echoing] Mom…
Your mother's not inside.
-But that's where I last saw her!
-[police officer] Let's go.
-[Camia] Hurry up!
-[Lily] Mom!
[Camia] Please don't hurt my daughter!
-[Tonio] Let go of me!
-[Camia] No!
[crying] Mom. She was really here! Mom!
Mom.
Where is Mom?
She was just there.
[wailing] Mom!
Mom!
[Raul] You killed them all off?
You didn't even spare the kid.
[tires screech]
To the people
who might know where Lily is…
[Julio] You idiot!
You caused a huge scandal!
People are talking about a child
missing from Poblacion Ardiente!
I want justice for my mom and dad!
Then we have a deal.
From now on, you'll be called Ivy Aguas.
[Lily] This was the only way
for me to be reborn
into a new me.
[theme music playing]